

Kareem Ismail

Full-Stack Engineer

Nationality: American

LINKS



LinkedIn



GitHub

CONTACT INFO

KareemTahalsmail@gmail.com
+1 (919) 928-3462

ABOUT ME

A driven tech advocate with a thirst for learning & delivering attractive, high-quality software with several years of experience as a Full-Stack Engineer. Here's a portfolio website for a peak at some personal projects and a more personal introduction.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages: [Java, Python, TypeScript, JavaScript]
- Front End: [Vue, React]
- Back-End / API: [Spring Boot, Flask, Express, Next.js]
- AWS: [Lambda, S3, SQS, ECS, EC2, Step-Functions]

EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack Engineer at Red Ventures (SC, USA)
 A multi-platform media company.

2024 - Present

- Updated and implemented backend microservices to supply our team's application with necessary data and models using Next.js using typescript. Involved S3, Lambda and multiple AWS services.
- Delivered frontend updates and provided new features to the <u>Coverage App</u> using Vue.js and Nuxt.
- Application Engineer II at <u>Vanguard</u> (Malvern, PA, USA)
 Largest provider of mutual funds and 2nd largest provider of ETFs.

2021 - 2024

- Updated, wrote and troubleshooted code for backend applications, addressing PROD issues, enhancing features, and introducing new functionalities by utilizing Java Spring Boot.
- Played a key role in the full SDLC, including creating ER diagrams, developing RESTFUL APIs, and implementing Lambdas for fund data sourcing and manipulation.
- Supervised associate developers to ensure a secure and efficient engineering approach in software delivery.
- Developed microservices for dynamic troubleshooting and operational improvements, collaborating with stakeholders and traders.
- Software Tutor at <u>Varsity Tutors</u> (Remote, USA)
 Innovative tutoring platform employing highly-skilled individuals.

2021 - Present

• Delivered comprehensive software, web, and game development instruction as an independent contractor, providing language lessons in Java, Python, TypeScript/JavaScript, and C#.

EDUCATION

- Lebanese American University BS in Computer Science
 - Graduated in 2020